<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.6">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-03-22T11:08:41+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">The Flair</title><subtitle>Here at The Flair we inspire and endeavor to share everything about technology like Softwares, Coding, etc., and provide our best about HOW TO tutorials and BEST OF every category in accordence to our knowledge.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Google’s coronavirus website finally launches alongside enhanced search results</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/google-coronavirus-website/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Google’s coronavirus website finally launches alongside enhanced search results" /><published>2020-03-21T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-03-21T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/google%20coronavirus-website</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/google-coronavirus-website/">&lt;p&gt;One week ago, President Donald Trump held a press conference wherein he claimed Google would be building a screening website for the coronavirus that would direct people to testing sites. As we learned in the following days, that wasn’t true. Google’s sister company Verily did launch such a site, but only for the Bay Area and reportedly it only offered tests to a very small number of people. Google, however, did say it would launch some sort of website and after a small delay, it’s here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alongside the website and potentially more importantly, Google will start providing more enhanced information cards for people who search for terms related to the coronavirus. There will be information tabs for symptoms, prevention, global statics, and locally relevant information. It will look a bit like this:
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/google/COVID_19_MOBILE_SEARCH.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;near by hospitals search result&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The website is at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/covid19&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;google.com/covid19&lt;/a&gt;. It does have useful resources, including a card that mimics what you see above. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.blog.google/products/search/connecting-people-covid-19-information-and-resources&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Google’s post announcing the site&lt;/a&gt; says that you will be able to find “state-based information, safety and prevention tips, search trends related to COVID-19, and further resources for individuals, educators and businesses.” Google emphasizes that it’s pulling information from “authoritative” sources like the WHO and the CDC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s only available in English right now, but a Google spokesperson tells The Verge that Spanish language support is soon to follow. The site was also designed with accessibility in mind, including with the larger fonts that Google usually uses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The website has videos in ASL, a global map showing confirmed cases by country, and plenty of information about Google’s other relief efforts — plus some feel-good YouTube videos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reading through that description, however, you’ll notice that it doesn’t include what Trump originally claimed it would. The nearest thing to finding a test is a drop-down menu that provides links to local websites — for example, choosing California provides a link to the California Department of Public Health.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/symptoms-testing/testing.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;CDC has a “self-checker” chatbot&lt;/a&gt; that Microsoft helped build, but the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/livecoverage/coronavirus/card/ih47JgriBzLY0nXEbncs&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;WSJ quoted an executive from a healthcare provider&lt;/a&gt; who put in a realistic context: “It’s just something consumers need now to help with anxiety.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other words, lots of big tech companies are making efforts to provide coronavirus-related support, but none of them are able to solve some of the biggest problems in the pandemic: access to testing and the impending crisis in our healthcare infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At some point in the future, Google may actually provide a questionnaire and information about local drive-thru testing locations. But a spokesperson says that the company won’t do so until there’s authoritative and trustworthy information on those sites. That could be a long time coming, unfortunately.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>nikhil</name></author><category term="corona virus" /><category term="google" /><category term="outbreak" /><category term="general" /><summary type="html">One week ago, President Donald Trump held a press conference wherein he claimed Google would be building a screening website for the coronavirus that would direct people to testing sites. As we learned in the following days, that wasn’t true. Google’s sister company Verily did launch such a site, but only for the Bay Area and reportedly it only offered tests to a very small number of people. Google, however, did say it would launch some sort of website and after a small delay, it’s here. Alongside the website and potentially more importantly, Google will start providing more enhanced information cards for people who search for terms related to the coronavirus. There will be information tabs for symptoms, prevention, global statics, and locally relevant information. It will look a bit like this: The website is at google.com/covid19. It does have useful resources, including a card that mimics what you see above. Google’s post announcing the site says that you will be able to find “state-based information, safety and prevention tips, search trends related to COVID-19, and further resources for individuals, educators and businesses.” Google emphasizes that it’s pulling information from “authoritative” sources like the WHO and the CDC. It’s only available in English right now, but a Google spokesperson tells The Verge that Spanish language support is soon to follow. The site was also designed with accessibility in mind, including with the larger fonts that Google usually uses. The website has videos in ASL, a global map showing confirmed cases by country, and plenty of information about Google’s other relief efforts — plus some feel-good YouTube videos. Reading through that description, however, you’ll notice that it doesn’t include what Trump originally claimed it would. The nearest thing to finding a test is a drop-down menu that provides links to local websites — for example, choosing California provides a link to the California Department of Public Health. Right now, the CDC has a “self-checker” chatbot that Microsoft helped build, but the WSJ quoted an executive from a healthcare provider who put in a realistic context: “It’s just something consumers need now to help with anxiety.” In other words, lots of big tech companies are making efforts to provide coronavirus-related support, but none of them are able to solve some of the biggest problems in the pandemic: access to testing and the impending crisis in our healthcare infrastructure. At some point in the future, Google may actually provide a questionnaire and information about local drive-thru testing locations. But a spokesperson says that the company won’t do so until there’s authoritative and trustworthy information on those sites. That could be a long time coming, unfortunately.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/google/COVID_19_Information___Resources___Google.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/google/COVID_19_Information___Resources___Google.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">A first look at Microsoft’s xCloud game streaming service for Windows PCs</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/microsoft-xcloud-game-streaming-service-for-windows/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A first look at Microsoft’s xCloud game streaming service for Windows PCs" /><published>2020-03-21T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-03-21T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/microsoft-xcloud-game-streaming-service-for-windows</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/microsoft-xcloud-game-streaming-service-for-windows/">&lt;p&gt;Microsoft has started testing its Project xCloud game streaming service for Windows 10 PCs this week. The software giant is making the preview version, which lets you stream Xbox games to a PC, available to all Microsoft employees. The Verge has been able to obtain exclusive screenshots of how xCloud will work on PCs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Microsoft has developed an Xbox Game Streaming app for Windows 10 that will be available in the Windows Store. Much like the Android or iOS versions, the app requires a Bluetooth Xbox One controller, a Microsoft account, and a good internet connection. The PC app will also support streaming games from an Xbox One console locally or remotely, instead of using Microsoft’s xCloud server blades.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/microsoft/xcloudpcwindows10_1.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 300px; display: inline&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/microsoft/xcloudpcwindows10_2.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 300px; display: inline&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/microsoft/xcloudpcwindows10_3.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 300px; display: inline&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/microsoft/xcloudpcwindows10_4.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 300px; display: inline&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/microsoft/xcloudpcwindows10_5.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 300px; display: inline&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/microsoft/xcloudpcwindows10_6.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 300px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a variety of games available to Microsoft employees to test, but the app is currently limited to 720p streams for now. “This internal preview is running at 720p resolution with 1080p just around the corner,” reveals an internal Microsoft support note.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The experience is very similar to what is available on Android and iOS, even down to the user interface and the way you access and stream games. It certainly looks ready to be tested broadly, and it’s likely that Microsoft will roll this out to external Xbox testers soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Microsoft also recently upgraded its xCloud server blades to include eight Xbox One S consoles in a single server instance. That’s up from the four the company was previously testing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;img src=”/assets/images/microsoft/xcloudblade.jpg” title=”Microsoft’s xCloud Server” alt=”Microsoft’s xCloud Server”;”/&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Microsoft is now working to eventually transition these xCloud servers to the Xbox Series X processor. This next-gen processor is far more powerful and capable of running four Xbox One S game sessions simultaneously on a single chip. It also includes a new built-in video encoder that is up to six times faster than the current external encoder that Microsoft uses on existing xCloud servers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Microsoft has committed to launching xCloud this year, with PS4 controller support and this Windows 10 streaming on the way. The Xbox maker is planning to integrate Project xCloud with Xbox Game Pass later this year, allowing players to stream games from the company’s subscription service directly from the cloud.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*image and post credits to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/&quot;&gt;The Verge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>nikhil</name></author><category term="microsoft" /><category term="xcloud" /><category term="windows" /><category term="gaming" /><summary type="html">Microsoft has started testing its Project xCloud game streaming service for Windows 10 PCs this week. The software giant is making the preview version, which lets you stream Xbox games to a PC, available to all Microsoft employees. The Verge has been able to obtain exclusive screenshots of how xCloud will work on PCs. Microsoft has developed an Xbox Game Streaming app for Windows 10 that will be available in the Windows Store. Much like the Android or iOS versions, the app requires a Bluetooth Xbox One controller, a Microsoft account, and a good internet connection. The PC app will also support streaming games from an Xbox One console locally or remotely, instead of using Microsoft’s xCloud server blades. There are a variety of games available to Microsoft employees to test, but the app is currently limited to 720p streams for now. “This internal preview is running at 720p resolution with 1080p just around the corner,” reveals an internal Microsoft support note. The experience is very similar to what is available on Android and iOS, even down to the user interface and the way you access and stream games. It certainly looks ready to be tested broadly, and it’s likely that Microsoft will roll this out to external Xbox testers soon. Microsoft also recently upgraded its xCloud server blades to include eight Xbox One S consoles in a single server instance. That’s up from the four the company was previously testing. &amp;lt;img src=”/assets/images/microsoft/xcloudblade.jpg” title=”Microsoft’s xCloud Server” alt=”Microsoft’s xCloud Server”;”/&amp;gt; Microsoft is now working to eventually transition these xCloud servers to the Xbox Series X processor. This next-gen processor is far more powerful and capable of running four Xbox One S game sessions simultaneously on a single chip. It also includes a new built-in video encoder that is up to six times faster than the current external encoder that Microsoft uses on existing xCloud servers. Microsoft has committed to launching xCloud this year, with PS4 controller support and this Windows 10 streaming on the way. The Xbox maker is planning to integrate Project xCloud with Xbox Game Pass later this year, allowing players to stream games from the company’s subscription service directly from the cloud. *image and post credits to The Verge</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/microsoft/xcloud.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/microsoft/xcloud.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Realme’s NARZO</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/realme-narzo-new-series/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Realme's NARZO" /><published>2020-03-20T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-03-20T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/realme-narzo-new-series</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/realme-narzo-new-series/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Realme has gained a lot of popularity since it’s launch of it’s first phone the realme 1 and It is the one of the fastest growing brand in INDIA&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has launched quiet a lot of popular phones under different series namely &lt;strong&gt;C&lt;/strong&gt; series, the &lt;strong&gt;number&lt;/strong&gt; series, the &lt;strong&gt;pro&lt;/strong&gt; series and the &lt;strong&gt;X&lt;/strong&gt; series and the company is soon going to 
launch a brand new series under the name &lt;strong&gt;NARZO&lt;/strong&gt; to take on the likes of redmi and poco.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Get ready to &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/FeelThePower?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;#FeelThePower&lt;/a&gt; as we unleash the bold and the unique with &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/realmeNarzo10?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;#realmeNarzo10&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/realmeNarzo10A?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;#realmeNarzo10A&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;br /&gt;Launching at 12:30 PM, 26th March on our official channels.&lt;br /&gt;Know more: &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/fMrX6tt9CJ&quot;&gt;https://t.co/fMrX6tt9CJ&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/0W2pZQoZAP&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/0W2pZQoZAP&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; realme (@realmemobiles) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/realmemobiles/status/1240859360428879872?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;March 20, 2020&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to a twitter post by realme, we will be getting two models under this brand name, namely 10 and 10a. 10 will end up being the high end or more flashy variant where as 10a will be the budget option coming under this series. More about this phone will be revealed on the launch date which will be on 26th march at 12:30PM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, what’s NARZO, who is it really and what does it mean to the public while much of the details regarding the new smartphone portfolio are not out yet but, we can gather a bits of information from the promotional twitter post and the teaser and &lt;strong&gt;it is clearly evident that will be focusing on the youth and it’s key focuses will be on design, performance and it’s styling&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>mohit</name></author><category term="realme" /><category term="narzo" /><category term="android phone" /><summary type="html">Realme has gained a lot of popularity since it’s launch of it’s first phone the realme 1 and It is the one of the fastest growing brand in INDIA It has launched quiet a lot of popular phones under different series namely C series, the number series, the pro series and the X series and the company is soon going to launch a brand new series under the name NARZO to take on the likes of redmi and poco.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/realme/2020-03-narzo.jpeg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/realme/2020-03-narzo.jpeg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Sourcerer a visual profile</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/sourcerer/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Sourcerer a visual profile" /><published>2020-03-20T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-03-20T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/sourcerer</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/sourcerer/">&lt;p&gt;Sourcerer is a visual profile for software engineers that helps you learn things about yourself, connect with others, and become a better engineer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As, per above line, you can know your self as a developer. It connects with github and gitlab and then read your complete public data and creates a visual format of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below are some of the images of my profile, it gives..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.&lt;/strong&gt; Overview&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/git/sourcerer/overview.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;overview&quot; style=&quot;border: 1px solid black;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.&lt;/strong&gt; Languages used&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/git/sourcerer/languages.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Languages used&quot; style=&quot;border: 1px solid black;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3.&lt;/strong&gt; Technologies used&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/git/sourcerer/technologies.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Technologies used&quot; style=&quot;border: 1px solid black;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4.&lt;/strong&gt; Fun facts&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/git/sourcerer/fun-facts.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Fun facts about you&quot; style=&quot;border: 1px solid black;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can also embed this easily to your LinkedIn, Twitter, Facebook and even to your Personal blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is my profile:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sourcerer.io/puneethkanna&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://avatars0.githubusercontent.com/u/40000406?v=4&quot; height=&quot;50px&quot; width=&quot;50px&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sourcerer.io/puneethkanna&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/Python-113%20commits-orange.svg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, you can share this to others for easily displaying your profile.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>puneeth</name></author><category term="sourcerer" /><category term="github" /><category term="visual profile" /><summary type="html">Sourcerer is a visual profile for software engineers that helps you learn things about yourself, connect with others, and become a better engineer.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/git/sourcerer/sourcerer.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/git/sourcerer/sourcerer.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">New iPad Pro 2020</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/new-ipad-pro-2020/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="New iPad Pro 2020" /><published>2020-03-19T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-03-19T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/new-ipad-pro-2020</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/new-ipad-pro-2020/">&lt;h1 id=&quot;apple-announces-the-new-ipad-pro&quot;&gt;Apple announces the new iPad Pro:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a lot of rumors apple finally announced the latest iPad Pro
the 11 inch iPad Pro starting at $799 and 12.9 inch one starting at $999.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has quite a lot going for it lets talk about it one by one, starting from&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.&lt;/strong&gt; The design its the same one as the previous gen iPad Pro and 
you will not be able to identify the previous from the latest one by just seeing the 
front which is covered with bezelless screen with a screen to body ratio of just below 83%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/apple/2020-ipad-design.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;2020 iPad Pro Design&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.&lt;/strong&gt; Talking about the screen its the same old IPS LCD panel, with 120hz refresh rate which is found in the previous generation of iPad Pro. We would like to have seen an Oled panel 
with the same 120hz refresh rate, but thats kind a nitpicking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/apple/2020-ipad-display.png&quot; alt=&quot;2020 iPad Pro Panel&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3.&lt;/strong&gt; Good froward taught about the back side the iPad Pro has got 2 new sensors, 
an ultra wide sensor of 12MP and Lidar sensor to aid with depth sensing and ARKIT stuff
attached in the same fashion like the iPhone 11.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/apple/2020-ipad-camera.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;2020 iPad Pro Camera&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4.&lt;/strong&gt; Talking about the Processing power,&lt;br /&gt;
the iPad Pro is powered by A12Z Bionic Chipset which according to apple is more powerful than windows PC. Going by the previous gen iPad Pro the claims might end up becoming true..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/apple/2020-ipad-processor.png&quot; alt=&quot;2020 iPad Pro ChipSet&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion&lt;/strong&gt; : Is the new iPad Pro worth paying attention to ? The simple answer would be Yes,
The iPad Pro is trying to be the everything machine be it a tablet or an laptop. It already 
was a great tablet but talking about laptop apple is trying its best thats evident by the fact that it now Provides Proper cursor support(mouse) for the iPad Pro and it has a smart keyboard which has a trackpad below the keyboard now its all upto the iPad OS which decides whether the iPad Pro can really be a computer for all intensive purposes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/apple/2020-ipad-keyboard-magic.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;2020 iPad Pro Magic Keyboard&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>mohit</name></author><category term="apple" /><category term="ipadpro" /><category term="tabletpc" /><category term="magic keyboard" /><category term="featured" /><category term="ios" /><summary type="html">Apple announces the new iPad Pro:</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/apple/2020-ipad.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/apple/2020-ipad.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">How to install Flutter in linux and Fix general problems</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/how-to-install-flutter-in-linux/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to install Flutter in linux and Fix general problems" /><published>2020-03-09T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-03-09T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/how-to-install-flutter-in-linux</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/how-to-install-flutter-in-linux/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;get-the-flutter-sdk&quot;&gt;Get the Flutter SDK&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.&lt;/strong&gt; First clone the SDK from&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;code-excerpt__code &quot;&gt;&lt;button class=&quot;code-excerpt__copy-btn btn&quot; type=&quot;button&quot; data-toggle=&quot;tooltip&quot; title=&quot;&quot; data-clipboard-text=&quot;git clone https://github.com/flutter/flutter.git -b stable&quot; data-original-title=&quot;Copy code&quot;&gt;  &lt;i class=&quot;material-icons&quot;&gt;content_copy&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/button&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;

&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;gp&quot;&gt;$&lt;/span&gt; git clone https://github.com/flutter/flutter.git -b stable 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.&lt;/strong&gt; Now, extract it in the desired location(preferred ‘home’ directory) by either right clicking and extract or by&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;code-excerpt__code &quot;&gt;&lt;button class=&quot;code-excerpt__copy-btn btn&quot; type=&quot;button&quot; data-toggle=&quot;tooltip&quot; title=&quot;&quot; data-clipboard-text=&quot;tar xf flutter_linux_v1.12.13+hotfix.8-stable.tar.xz&quot; data-original-title=&quot;Copy code&quot;&gt;  &lt;i class=&quot;material-icons&quot;&gt;content_copy&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/button&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;

&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;gp&quot;&gt;$&lt;/span&gt; tar xf flutter_linux_v1.12.13+hotfix.8-stable.tar.xz
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3.&lt;/strong&gt; Now add flutter to your PATH&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;code-excerpt__code &quot;&gt;&lt;button class=&quot;code-excerpt__copy-btn btn&quot; type=&quot;button&quot; data-toggle=&quot;tooltip&quot; title=&quot;&quot; data-clipboard-text=&quot;export PATH=&amp;quot;$PATH:`pwd`/flutter/bin&amp;quot;&quot; data-original-title=&quot;Copy code&quot;&gt;  &lt;i class=&quot;material-icons&quot;&gt;content_copy&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/button&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;

&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;gp&quot;&gt;$&lt;/span&gt; export PATH=&quot;$PATH:`pwd`/flutter/bin&quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4.&lt;/strong&gt; The last step is running&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;code-excerpt__code &quot;&gt;&lt;button class=&quot;code-excerpt__copy-btn btn&quot; type=&quot;button&quot; data-toggle=&quot;tooltip&quot; title=&quot;&quot; data-clipboard-text=&quot;flutter doctor&quot; data-original-title=&quot;Copy code&quot;&gt;  &lt;i class=&quot;material-icons&quot;&gt;content_copy&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/button&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;

&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;gp&quot;&gt;$&lt;/span&gt; flutter doctor
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This command checks your environment and displays a report to the terminal window. The Dart SDK is bundled with Flutter; it is not necessary to install Dart separately. Check the output carefully for other software you might need to install or further tasks to perform (shown in bold text).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note: Android studio is mandatory for running Flutter&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;after-this-many-people-may-face-issues-with-android-studio-for-example-like-this&quot;&gt;After this many people may face issues with android studio. For example like this&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;[-] Android toolchain - develop for Android devices
    • Android SDK at /Users/obiwan/Library/Android/sdk
    ✗ Android SDK is missing command line tools; download from https://goo.gl/XxQghQ
    • Try re-installing or updating your Android SDK,
      visit https://flutter.dev/setup/#android-setup for detailed instructions.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;to-resolve-these-issues-even-after-installing-android-studio-follow-the-below-steps&quot;&gt;To, resolve these issues even after installing Android studio, follow the below steps&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.&lt;/strong&gt; Open android studio and then goto settings and then Android SDK.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/android/flutter-install-1.png&quot; alt=&quot;Android-studio-settings-sdk&quot; /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;2.&lt;/strong&gt; Now UNCHECK the “Hide Obsolete packages” and then verify all the below mentioned are installed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Android SDK Build-Tools&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Android SDK Command-line Tools&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Android SDK Platform-Tools&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Android SDK Tools(Obsolete) [This is generally hidden until you uncheck the Hide Obsolete Packages]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/android/flutter-install-2.png&quot; alt=&quot;Android-SDK-Tools(Obsolete)-Install&quot; /&gt;
Install(Tick all the above and click apply, wait until download and installation of the above packages) the above packages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, goto Terminal and run&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;code-excerpt__code &quot;&gt;&lt;button class=&quot;code-excerpt__copy-btn btn&quot; type=&quot;button&quot; data-toggle=&quot;tooltip&quot; title=&quot;&quot; data-clipboard-text=&quot;flutter doctor&quot; data-original-title=&quot;Copy code&quot;&gt;  &lt;i class=&quot;material-icons&quot;&gt;content_copy&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/button&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;

&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;gp&quot;&gt;$&lt;/span&gt; flutter doctor
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By this time it should work. If it is not working close and open the terminal and set the PATH and try again.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>puneeth</name></author><category term="os" /><category term="linux" /><category term="windows" /><category term="student" /><category term="google" /><summary type="html">Get the Flutter SDK</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/flutter.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/flutter.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Student developer windows and linux usage</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/student-developer-windows-and-linux-usage/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Student developer windows and linux usage" /><published>2020-03-09T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-03-09T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/student-developer-windows-and-linux-usage</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/student-developer-windows-and-linux-usage/">&lt;p&gt;Generally, many developers prefer to use either linux or mac. But, mac is a very costly thing where students cannot afford, but it is secured.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now coming to linux, we can’t just define it. It is very addictable using linux.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/winvslinux.png&quot; alt=&quot;WindowsvsLinux&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;1-performance&quot;&gt;1. Performance:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we talk about performance, Linux runs faster than windows, even with the improved graphics compared to previous it is faster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we open android studio in windows whole system goes down, but in linux we can able to run some other programs parallelly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;2-updates&quot;&gt;2. Updates:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Windows updates are very irritating, they need need to reboot for every update and it takes a lot of time to update i.e reboot. But in linux the updates are very fast and very rare updates need reboot that too it takes very less time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;3-flavours&quot;&gt;3. Flavours:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Windows only has one theme, and which is less customizable. Linux has many flavours and many of them are highly customizable. Some of them are Linux mint, Ubuntu, Kali Linux and many more..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;4-security&quot;&gt;4. Security:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No system is safe, when comes to security, though Linux is more secure compared to Windows.
There are various constraints for this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Windows is widely is used OS, so it is a target.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Windows is preparatory software i.e source code is hidden, so bugs and flaws can only fixed by the company. But Linux is opensource so anyone can fix it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;5-support&quot;&gt;5. Support:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Microsoft Windows support isn’t bad, but linux has more forums and chatroom’s and websites where support comes from enthusiastic, where as for windows we should relay on the Company forums where employees give answers much time.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>puneeth</name></author><category term="os" /><category term="linux" /><category term="windows" /><category term="student" /><summary type="html">Generally, many developers prefer to use either linux or mac. But, mac is a very costly thing where students cannot afford, but it is secured.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/studentdev.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/studentdev.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">How to Rank on First Page of Google</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/how-to-rank-on-first-page-of-google/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to Rank on First Page of Google" /><published>2020-03-03T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-03-03T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/how-to-rank-on-first-page-of-google</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/how-to-rank-on-first-page-of-google/">&lt;p&gt;As we all know, the biggest challenge in internet marketing is getting traffic to your website. However difficult it may be, it is a must if you want to be successful. You could pay for Google AdWords, and pray that your campaign doesn’t get slapped by Google, or you could spend a few extra minutes every day, and get a better listing with more traffic for free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So how did I get my listing on the first page of Google?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am going to show you in 5 simple steps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ok, here it goes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step 1&lt;/strong&gt;
Create a blog – 10 minutes unless you already have a blog or website. Setting up a blog is very easy. Go to Blogger, register for a free Blogger account, choose a name for your blog (being very careful to give a name that applies to what you will be writing articles about), write your first post to introduce the blog, and then move on to step 2.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step 2&lt;/strong&gt;
Write an article or press release – 10-30 minutes depending on the length. Be careful not to “sell” anything in your article. You should be giving advice, reviewing a product, or something of that nature. Make sure you place a link to your blog at the end of the article in the bio box.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step 3&lt;/strong&gt;
Create a Title for your article and make sure that it is a popular phrase – one that will be searched for. You can use the free keyword tools for this. You want to search for your phrase using quotes (“), and look at the results number at the top right of the search results — if the results are under 5000, and there are people paying for ads using that search term (look for the sponsored listings on the right hand side), then chances are you have found a winner. Use that for the name of your article. Always write your article and save it to your computer, as you will want to submit it to more than one article directory. Copy/paste your article in to 4 or 5 free article submission sites, and then copy and paste it to your blog using the same title as the “Blog Post Title”. If you prefer to just link from your blog to the article, you can do that as well, but the idea is not just posting to article directories, it is adding “important” content to your blog. Once you have completed this step, move on to step 4.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step 4&lt;/strong&gt;
Many of the article submission sites allow you to use the “Add This” feature, which allows you to submit your article link to Social Networking Sites. Many online marketers are realizing the importance of doing this, so I would not skip this step.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step 5&lt;/strong&gt;
Search for your title in 24 hours and find it on the first page of Google.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Folks, it does not get any better than this. Imagine having 10-20 articles listed per month. Do you know how much traffic that would create? And to think that if you write good content, your articles could show up for months or years to come!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The great thing about this is that even if you have never written an article in your life, once you write one, and it gets listed by Google, you will be hooked. And don’t forget, you are getting all of this accomplished absolutely free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Forget about all of the SEO, and maintaining a website. Choose your title wisely, and you will be successful.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>nikhil</name></author><category term="seo" /><category term="google" /><summary type="html">As we all know, the biggest challenge in internet marketing is getting traffic to your website. However difficult it may be, it is a must if you want to be successful. You could pay for Google AdWords, and pray that your campaign doesn’t get slapped by Google, or you could spend a few extra minutes every day, and get a better listing with more traffic for free. So how did I get my listing on the first page of Google? I am going to show you in 5 simple steps. Ok, here it goes: Step 1 Create a blog – 10 minutes unless you already have a blog or website. Setting up a blog is very easy. Go to Blogger, register for a free Blogger account, choose a name for your blog (being very careful to give a name that applies to what you will be writing articles about), write your first post to introduce the blog, and then move on to step 2. Step 2 Write an article or press release – 10-30 minutes depending on the length. Be careful not to “sell” anything in your article. You should be giving advice, reviewing a product, or something of that nature. Make sure you place a link to your blog at the end of the article in the bio box. Step 3 Create a Title for your article and make sure that it is a popular phrase – one that will be searched for. You can use the free keyword tools for this. You want to search for your phrase using quotes (“), and look at the results number at the top right of the search results — if the results are under 5000, and there are people paying for ads using that search term (look for the sponsored listings on the right hand side), then chances are you have found a winner. Use that for the name of your article. Always write your article and save it to your computer, as you will want to submit it to more than one article directory. Copy/paste your article in to 4 or 5 free article submission sites, and then copy and paste it to your blog using the same title as the “Blog Post Title”. If you prefer to just link from your blog to the article, you can do that as well, but the idea is not just posting to article directories, it is adding “important” content to your blog. Once you have completed this step, move on to step 4. Step 4 Many of the article submission sites allow you to use the “Add This” feature, which allows you to submit your article link to Social Networking Sites. Many online marketers are realizing the importance of doing this, so I would not skip this step. Step 5 Search for your title in 24 hours and find it on the first page of Google. Folks, it does not get any better than this. Imagine having 10-20 articles listed per month. Do you know how much traffic that would create? And to think that if you write good content, your articles could show up for months or years to come! The great thing about this is that even if you have never written an article in your life, once you write one, and it gets listed by Google, you will be hooked. And don’t forget, you are getting all of this accomplished absolutely free. Forget about all of the SEO, and maintaining a website. Choose your title wisely, and you will be successful.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/google/how-to-rank-on-first-page-of-google.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/google/how-to-rank-on-first-page-of-google.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Challenges Faced By Android App Developers</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/challenges-faced-by-android-app-developers/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Challenges Faced By Android App Developers" /><published>2020-03-02T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-03-02T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/challenges-faced-by-android-app-developers</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/challenges-faced-by-android-app-developers/">&lt;p&gt;While developing mobile apps, businesses target Android due to its massive worldwide mobile operating system market share. Alphabet has made Android available as an open source mobile platform. Also, it updates the mobile operating system at regular intervals with new features and enhancements. But the penetration rate of individual versions of the mobile operating system differs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alphabet does not regulate the Android smartphones, tablets, and phablets manufactured by various companies. Hence, the devices manufactured by different companies come with varying hardware features despite being powered by the same version of Android. That is why; it becomes essential for developers build mobile apps by targeting a wide range of devices powered by different versions of Android.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While planning, developing, and testing the mobile app, they need to focus extensively on its accessibility, functionality, performance, usability, and security of the mobile app to keep the users engaged regardless of their choice of Android device. Also, they need to explore ways to make the app deliver personalized user experience across varying devices and operating system version. They further need to address a number of common challenges to develop a robust Android app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Understanding 7 Common Challenges Faced by Android App Developers&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;1) Software Fragmentation&lt;/strong&gt;
As mentioned earlier, the market share of individual versions of Android differs. According to the latest data released by Google, the most recent version of its mobile operating system – Nougat – has a market share lower than its predecessors – Marshmallow, Lollipop and KitKat. Each new version of Android comes with several new features and enhancements. The developers have to include specific features in the app to make it deliver optimal user experience by taking advantage of these new features. At the same time, they also need to ensure that the app delivers rich and personalized user experience on devices powered by older versions of Android. The developers have to target multiple versions of Android to make the application popular and profitable in the short run.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2) Varying Hardware Features&lt;/strong&gt;
Unlike other mobile operating systems, Android is open source. Alphabet allows device manufacturers to customize its operating system according to their specific needs. Also, it does not regulate the Android devices launched by various manufacturers. Hence, the devices come with varying hardware features despite being powered by the same version of Android. For instance, two devices powered by Android Nougat may differ from each other in the category of display screen size, resolution, camera and other hardware features. While developing an Android app, the developers need to ensure that it delivers personalized experience to each user by accessing all hardware features of his device.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3) No Uniform User Interface Designing Process or Rules&lt;/strong&gt;
Google has not released any common user interface (UI) designing process or rules for the mobile app developers. Hence, most developers build Android apps without following any standard UI development process or rules. When the developers create custom UI interfaces in their own way, the apps do not look or function consistently across different devices. The incompatibility and diversity of the UI affects the user experience delivered by the Android app directly. The smart developers opt for responsive layout to keep the UI consistent across many devices. Also, the developers have to test the UI of their mobile app comprehensively by combining both real devices and emulators. But often developers find it daunting to design a UI that make the app look consistent across various Android devices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4) API Incompatibility&lt;/strong&gt;
Most developers use third-party APIs to enhance the mobile app’s functionality and interoperability. But the quality of third-party APIs available for Android app developers differs. Some APIs are designed for a particular version of Android. Hence, these APIs do not work on devices powered by different versions of the mobile operating system. The developers have to explore ways to make a single API work on different versions of Android. But they often find it challenging to make the app work smoothly on different Android devices with the same set of APIs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5) Security Flaws&lt;/strong&gt;
Its open source nature makes it easier for device manufacturers to customize Android according to their specific needs. But the openness and its massive market share made Android vulnerable to frequent security attacks. There are many instances when security of millions of Android devices has been impacted by security flaws or bugs like Stagefright, ‘Certifi-gate’ mRST, FakeID, Installer Hijacking and TowelRoot. The developers have to include robust security features in the application and use latest encryption mechanism to keep the user information secure despite targeted security attacks and security flaws in Android.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6) Android Search Engine Visibility&lt;/strong&gt;
The latest data posted on various website depict that Google Play Store has a much higher number of mobile apps than Apple App Store. Also, a large percentage of Android device users prefer free apps to paid apps. Hence, the developers have to promote their mobile apps aggressively to accomplish higher download numbers and implement app monetization options. They also need to implement a comprehensive digital marketing strategy to promote the app by targeting the most relevant users. Many developers have to avail the services of digital marketing professionals to promote their apps aggressively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7) Patent Issues&lt;/strong&gt;
The users have option to choose from several Android apps offering identical features and functionalities. But developers often find it daunting to build apps with unique features and functionality. They often include features and functionalities in the app that make it similar to a number of apps available in the same category in the Play store. Unlike Apple, Google does not implement stringent guidelines to evaluate the quality of new apps being submitted to its app store. Lack of standardized quality assessment guidelines often make developers address issues related to patent. Some developers have to design and modify their apps in future to avoid patent issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most Android app developers nowadays work in agile development environment to build Android apps rapidly. They have to coordinate consistently with QA professionals, and participate actively in the mobile app testing process. Hence, the developers also need to address a number of common issues in Android app testing.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>nikhil</name></author><category term="google" /><summary type="html">While developing mobile apps, businesses target Android due to its massive worldwide mobile operating system market share. Alphabet has made Android available as an open source mobile platform. Also, it updates the mobile operating system at regular intervals with new features and enhancements. But the penetration rate of individual versions of the mobile operating system differs. Alphabet does not regulate the Android smartphones, tablets, and phablets manufactured by various companies. Hence, the devices manufactured by different companies come with varying hardware features despite being powered by the same version of Android. That is why; it becomes essential for developers build mobile apps by targeting a wide range of devices powered by different versions of Android. While planning, developing, and testing the mobile app, they need to focus extensively on its accessibility, functionality, performance, usability, and security of the mobile app to keep the users engaged regardless of their choice of Android device. Also, they need to explore ways to make the app deliver personalized user experience across varying devices and operating system version. They further need to address a number of common challenges to develop a robust Android app. Understanding 7 Common Challenges Faced by Android App Developers 1) Software Fragmentation As mentioned earlier, the market share of individual versions of Android differs. According to the latest data released by Google, the most recent version of its mobile operating system – Nougat – has a market share lower than its predecessors – Marshmallow, Lollipop and KitKat. Each new version of Android comes with several new features and enhancements. The developers have to include specific features in the app to make it deliver optimal user experience by taking advantage of these new features. At the same time, they also need to ensure that the app delivers rich and personalized user experience on devices powered by older versions of Android. The developers have to target multiple versions of Android to make the application popular and profitable in the short run. 2) Varying Hardware Features Unlike other mobile operating systems, Android is open source. Alphabet allows device manufacturers to customize its operating system according to their specific needs. Also, it does not regulate the Android devices launched by various manufacturers. Hence, the devices come with varying hardware features despite being powered by the same version of Android. For instance, two devices powered by Android Nougat may differ from each other in the category of display screen size, resolution, camera and other hardware features. While developing an Android app, the developers need to ensure that it delivers personalized experience to each user by accessing all hardware features of his device. 3) No Uniform User Interface Designing Process or Rules Google has not released any common user interface (UI) designing process or rules for the mobile app developers. Hence, most developers build Android apps without following any standard UI development process or rules. When the developers create custom UI interfaces in their own way, the apps do not look or function consistently across different devices. The incompatibility and diversity of the UI affects the user experience delivered by the Android app directly. The smart developers opt for responsive layout to keep the UI consistent across many devices. Also, the developers have to test the UI of their mobile app comprehensively by combining both real devices and emulators. But often developers find it daunting to design a UI that make the app look consistent across various Android devices. 4) API Incompatibility Most developers use third-party APIs to enhance the mobile app’s functionality and interoperability. But the quality of third-party APIs available for Android app developers differs. Some APIs are designed for a particular version of Android. Hence, these APIs do not work on devices powered by different versions of the mobile operating system. The developers have to explore ways to make a single API work on different versions of Android. But they often find it challenging to make the app work smoothly on different Android devices with the same set of APIs. 5) Security Flaws Its open source nature makes it easier for device manufacturers to customize Android according to their specific needs. But the openness and its massive market share made Android vulnerable to frequent security attacks. There are many instances when security of millions of Android devices has been impacted by security flaws or bugs like Stagefright, ‘Certifi-gate’ mRST, FakeID, Installer Hijacking and TowelRoot. The developers have to include robust security features in the application and use latest encryption mechanism to keep the user information secure despite targeted security attacks and security flaws in Android. 6) Android Search Engine Visibility The latest data posted on various website depict that Google Play Store has a much higher number of mobile apps than Apple App Store. Also, a large percentage of Android device users prefer free apps to paid apps. Hence, the developers have to promote their mobile apps aggressively to accomplish higher download numbers and implement app monetization options. They also need to implement a comprehensive digital marketing strategy to promote the app by targeting the most relevant users. Many developers have to avail the services of digital marketing professionals to promote their apps aggressively. 7) Patent Issues The users have option to choose from several Android apps offering identical features and functionalities. But developers often find it daunting to build apps with unique features and functionality. They often include features and functionalities in the app that make it similar to a number of apps available in the same category in the Play store. Unlike Apple, Google does not implement stringent guidelines to evaluate the quality of new apps being submitted to its app store. Lack of standardized quality assessment guidelines often make developers address issues related to patent. Some developers have to design and modify their apps in future to avoid patent issues. Most Android app developers nowadays work in agile development environment to build Android apps rapidly. They have to coordinate consistently with QA professionals, and participate actively in the mobile app testing process. Hence, the developers also need to address a number of common issues in Android app testing.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/android/challenges-android-developers.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/android/challenges-android-developers.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Install Google Chrome in Ubuntu/Linux</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/googlechrome-for-ubuntu/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Install Google Chrome in Ubuntu/Linux" /><published>2020-02-29T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-02-29T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/googlechrome-for-ubuntu</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/googlechrome-for-ubuntu/">&lt;p&gt;Google chrome is one of the most used popular browsers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Firefox has improved a lot lately and is a better choice specially from the privacy point of view. However, if you are an ardent fan of Google Chrome, I won’t force you to ditch Chrome and move to Firefox.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ofcourse chrome is available for linux, but Google Chrome is not an open source and if you try to install Google Chrome from Ubuntu Software Center, you won’t find it there. It will probably suggest installing Chromium (the open source project Chrome is derived from). Chromium is similar to Chrome but it’s still not the real Google Chrome..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, we wil see the installation of google chrome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are two methods to install Google Chrome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Graphical install&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Command line install&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;1-graphical-method-begginers-method&quot;&gt;1. Graphical method [Begginer’s method]&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are new to ubuntu and Linux world, this method is preferable(If you interested in administration, you can give a try with command line)
Firstly go to the official website for downloading chrome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/chrome/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;button style=&quot;cursor: pointer; color: whitesmoke; background-color: black; display: inline-block;text-decoration: none; border: none; max-width: 100%; font-size:20px&quot;&gt;Download Google chrome
&lt;/button&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You will see a download link there, now click the “Download chrome” button to download.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/linux/chrome-download.png&quot; alt=&quot;Chrome download page&quot; style=&quot;max-width: 100%; border:0;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, you can see tat it is asking to select between two versions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/linux/chrome-select.png&quot; alt=&quot;Chrome download page&quot; style=&quot;max-width: 100%; border:0;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to install chrome for other linux systems like Fedora, openSUSE download the “rpm package”, but we are now installing it for Ubuntu, download the ubuntu package.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After downloading, open the downloaded file by double clicking it. Now,Ubuntu software center is opened and chrome will be staged for installation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/linux/chrome-install.png&quot; alt=&quot;Chrome download page&quot; style=&quot;max-width: 100%; border:0;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, just press “install”, google chrome will be installed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;2-command-line-method-advanced-or-interested-users&quot;&gt;2. Command line Method (Advanced or Interested user’s)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This process is generally annoying for begginer users. So, follow the below steps carefully.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To install chrome we need to download it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;wget https://dl.google.com/linux/direct/google-chrome-stable_current_amd64.deb
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Type the command in he terminal&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the download process is finised, try to install it using the following command in the directory where you have downloaded&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo dpkg -i google-chrome-stable_current_amd64.deb
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s it, your system will be installed with chrome!!
Coming to updating the chrome, you can update it while you are updatong your systems.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>puneeth</name></author><category term="linux" /><category term="PC" /><category term="Operating system" /><category term="chrome" /><category term="google" /><summary type="html">Google chrome is one of the most used popular browsers.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/linux/ubuntu-logo.gif" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/linux/ubuntu-logo.gif" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>